we flew up just to the neighbouring
lake up to Tuiton Lake
And now I know it's like, you know,
as far as all of the places
in that upper Stikine
go, it's, you know, it's right there.
A lot of people have been there
before, but.
And Ray has been there a million times,
but to me, it was the most remote place
I'd ever been by far.
I just got, you know,
taken from Laslui camp with Ray in the cab.
To Tuiton my mind is like blowing up.
I'm like, so we landed there.
I'm expecting some more, like,
manual labour.
I think there was actually my first job
was I had to, like,
go in their old hunting cabin and
set all the traps with peanut butter
and whatever dodging this freaking porcupine
that kinda made it its house.
But after that Ray took me over to,
the outlet of upper Tuiton
gave me a fly rod
and, was like, you know,
you know, check this out, fish.
This and go down
this little creek here, fish that,
and then I'll meet you down at the
at the next lake.
And he got in his plane and took off.
He's like, I'll see you in a couple hours
and was like, gone.
And that was like a whole new level
of like,
whoa, I'm in, I'm in it.
I'm in the wild.
And,
it was an awesome time.
Ray did not come back in two hours.
He came back in, like, five hours.
But I had hoot it was a good time.
But the cool thing about guiding
is you get to give that experience
to other people.
And,
that was probably the moment for me
where it went
from, like, I'm trying out this job in a
meeting room and all this stuff to, like,
whoa, like I am.
I love this place.
I love this place,
and I never want to stop coming here,
and I, I hope it never changes.
And I would put a lot of work
into making sure
that other people can have this experience
and that doesn't change.
My favourite place up north is probably
Hotleskwa Lake.
It's just above the lodge,
it’s the headwaters of the Stikine,
just above Laslui.
And, it's one of the very,
very top tribes
of the Stikine.
And it's a fjordal lake,
very like steep cliffs.
And just
it's wild. It's wild.
It can be peaceful and and idyllic,
with birds chirping and flowers blooming,
but most days it'll at least be gnarly
for a bit, like storms are flying through
and you can't see them
till they come over the hill.
It's glacier fed,
so the back end of this lake is maybe like
20km long or something.
The back end has this beautiful blue
glacial till.
And then as you move along to the outlet,
it kind of clears up and clears
up and clears up and gets
more like a kind of a rocky mountain.
Banff Jasper, blue.
But anyone you bring up
there is just like.
And, that's one place I never got.
Never got sick of. All seasons
and every time I went up there, it's just.
Yeah Hotleskwa Lake,,
thatwas my favourite spot.